<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel Notes on Burak Sina Akbudak</title><link>https://fansesi.github.io/categories/travel-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Travel Notes on Burak Sina Akbudak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fansesi.github.io/categories/travel-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ISEF Event</title><link>https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note (EN):&lt;/strong> If you know Turkish, I highly recommend you to read this article in Turkish. Beacuse it is the original version.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Not (TR):&lt;/strong> Yazının orijinal versiyonu Türkçe olduğundan dolayı eğer biliyorsanız bu yazıyı Türkçe okumanızı tavsiye ederim.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The time has finally come.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-1---travel">Day 1 - Travel
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We arrived at the airport without any issues in the morning. We&amp;rsquo;ll wait for about an hour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got called from the counter. Funny thing to be called. They wanted to call someone from the ISEF team but called me instead. No big deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had no trouble placing the guitar. There was space for it as cabin baggage, but I don&amp;rsquo;t expect the same for the US flight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We reached Istanbul Airport. It&amp;rsquo;s still as huge as ever since I last left it. It took about 20 minutes just to get to the parking position.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While waiting for the LA flight, we didn&amp;rsquo;t do much. Time passed quickly with chats and talks. Refilling my water was a good idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re on the plane now. The guitar doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit in the overhead compartment. It&amp;rsquo;s between my legs for now, but the flight attendants said they&amp;rsquo;d help. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally managed to store the guitar. For about 15 minutes since boarding, I was nervously thinking about where to place it. Once boarding was complete, I found a large space for it without any issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I&amp;rsquo;ve had this menu before, probably on my way to Brussels. It was quite satisfying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is really a ridiculously long journey. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through most of what I prepared (one of two movies, calculus study, geography book, many of the albums I downloaded) and there&amp;rsquo;s still two hours left. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll eat the second meal, work a bit more on my presentation, and listen to music. Hopefully, we reach the hotel safely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We waited for about 1-1.5 hours during the transfer. We&amp;rsquo;ve collected our luggage but at what cost. We&amp;rsquo;re resting a bit on the side while most of our group is still upstairs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time to sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-2---shopping">Day 2 - Shopping
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Woke up and took a shower. My roommate is a good guy. We didn&amp;rsquo;t talk much since we were tired. We&amp;rsquo;re waiting to go down for breakfast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had an Oreo waffle for breakfast. As they said, the portion was big. I got full but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very healthy breakfast, lots of sugar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We went back to the hotel and waited for about half an hour until the exhibition opened. Then, after waiting for those who were late, we went to the LA Convention Center. We hung out with a Ukrainian guy while waiting in front of the center. We handed over our passports and registration forms and are now waiting to register.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Got our cards and badges. Kept them nicely, hopefully, I won&amp;rsquo;t lose them. There&amp;rsquo;s a small bag too, cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/1.webp"
width="2048"
height="1536"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/1_hu15954084404456394209.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/1_hu9371719247449872409.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image of the Türkiye team in front of the famous ISEF name wall."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, we&amp;rsquo;re calling an Uber with TÜBİTAK personnel to go to the outlet. Chatting and walking around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Passed by Corridor Digital. Didn&amp;rsquo;t see the building fully but saw the neighborhood, and it really looks just like in the videos. Pretty cool!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a nice Uber ride, we arrived at the outlet. It&amp;rsquo;s just like Forum Aydın tbh. The whole outlet logic is the same as ours. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit crowded since it&amp;rsquo;s Saturday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing this because Leylek asked, he bought a necklace for his mom from Swarovski. Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shopping part was boring. No electronics store, they said maybe they&amp;rsquo;d take us to Best Buy later. Hopefully, I can get my headphones there. So far, just hanging out with our group. Dinner soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m hungry. My battery is at 5%. Not good.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-3---initial-setup">Day 3 - Initial Setup
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As soon as I got back, I fell asleep. Sent a few voice messages and slept. Shopping mall days aren&amp;rsquo;t really my thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you sleep at 8:30 PM, naturally, you can&amp;rsquo;t sleep through the night. Woke up around 4:30 AM feeling rested enough. Decided to use the bathroom first, then called our folks. Talked to people for two hours. First my mom, then my brother, then the guys from our dorm, and then my dad woke up, so I talked to my parents again. It was nice. Probably won&amp;rsquo;t find time again. We&amp;rsquo;ll see. Got another two hours before we leave the hotel. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably work on my presentation. Then breakfast and head to the venue to put up the poster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot happened. Now I&amp;rsquo;m writing them quickly. We arrived at the venue, put up our posters first. Messed up the middle part initially but managed to fix it. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it alone. Thankfully, later Nisa helped and we managed. After completing the poster, we went to the HUB, checked in, and started waiting for the inspection. Just as I was about to say we were waiting, the initial inspector arrived. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even pinned my summary to the table yet. He was very helpful. They are very calm. The guy stayed with me for about 15-20 minutes, at least it felt that way. Afterward, the second inspector came. An old, sweet lady. Then, I QR scanned the guitar and laptop. You scan them every time you enter and exit. Thus, I passed the inspection process in one go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/2.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/2_hu11493372293292628887.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/2_hu7696796189506804141.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="My stand, after the inspection process."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I refilled my water and went for lunch. Grabbed a cheese pizza and ate it. We hadn&amp;rsquo;t eaten anything in the morning, so it was quite satisfying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the career fair started. There&amp;rsquo;s a thing called a passport where you collect stamps from 10 groups. I collected all in an hour. Stupidly spent another hour looking for where to take it, but it was in the same place all along. Anyway, sorted that out. Hopefully, I&amp;rsquo;ll win $25 from the ISEF Store. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll buy a t-shirt, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My Danish friend arrived. Came while I was talking to a journalist lady. Then I went over to her for a chat. There&amp;rsquo;s a pin exchange later. Until then, we have a lot of free time. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably play my guitar. I took a nice video of the surroundings, need to send it to the groups and people but I can&amp;rsquo;t connect to the internet somehow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won the passport thing! Went with Leylek. Initially, we thought of getting 3 mugs. But there wasn&amp;rsquo;t one for our category. So, I got a t-shirt. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool. There was a better one, but it was sold out and won&amp;rsquo;t be restocked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wandered around aimlessly. Wish I had socialized with other projects. A mistake, I made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the evening, there was a pin exchange. Breaking the ice for 1600 people isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. The environment was noisy, making proper conversation almost impossible. In the first hour, we shared all the Turkey pins with Leylek. Later we sat with the TÜBİTAK team, chatted, etc. Then went back and went to bed directly. It was tiring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-4---symposiums">Day 4 - Symposiums
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Got up in the morning, went down as if to have breakfast but didn&amp;rsquo;t eat. Chatted a bit with our folks. Missed the first group and went to the venue with the second group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First thing, we took a photo with the Turkish flag. It felt good. I love representing my country. Then we went to the symposiums.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first one was about how judges evaluate. Good presentation. My notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Elevator pitch is about 30 sec.&lt;br>
If the scheduled judge doesn&amp;rsquo;t come, say it to the cochairs.
Printed name has priority when two judges come.
Judges shouldn&amp;rsquo;t leave after 5 mins.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The second one was about how to apply to a university. My notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I hope the most important thing about me is not Yale.&amp;rdquo;
If you have an interdisciplinary person, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to think about one of the disciplines overshadowing the other. &amp;ldquo;Put yourself on the table.&amp;rdquo;
Your interest can and will probably change.
About the questions: it&amp;rsquo;s okay to ask, you know. We won&amp;rsquo;t remember it after reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The third one was about writing essays. My notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Anxiety: &amp;ldquo;My essay won&amp;rsquo;t stand out.&amp;rdquo;, everyone have that.
Why even essay: &amp;ldquo;You are more than your GPA.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Essays are not resumes. We already have your resume. We look for stories and experiences.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Let your personality shine. If you are funny, write an essay that has jokes in it.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Multiple people look at your application. We literally project your essay onto a wall and read it with 3 officers, DA, and a faculty member. We care!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Afterward, went to the venue and worked a bit on my presentation. Our folks came and went. Didn&amp;rsquo;t go for lunch today. I could have eaten, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it. After the symposiums, it was around 3 PM. I suggested going to BestBuy to TÜBİTAK personnel. He said it would be better to go tomorrow, as it might be difficult to make it back for the opening ceremony. I trusted his judgment and didn&amp;rsquo;t insist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we went back to the hotel, played the guitar for an hour, then headed back to the venue for the opening ceremony.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Got in line for the opening ceremony, and the line got so long behind us. Glad we went early, though it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem early to us when we arrived. Not much to say about it. Nice, good hype. The VTRs were a bit lackluster now that I think about it. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, the important one is the awards ceremony.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-5---student-mixer">Day 5 - Student Mixer
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I woke up early in the morning. I researched a few questions I had in mind and took notes on them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interestingly, we didn&amp;rsquo;t wait for 15 minutes this time; we left the hotel after a short delay of 2-3 minutes. Today, since VIPs and sponsors would be visiting, people were dressed in business attire. I wore a ISEF t-shirt, hope it won&amp;rsquo;t be a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon arriving at the venue, they let in the problematic projects and did a final D&amp;amp;S check. Instead of waiting in an endless line, we sat on the sidelines. Then we went inside and moved to our spot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While sitting and playing the guitar, two or three interested people came by. I presented a little, chatted, and then hung out with the TECA team for a while. Since they are all Americans, their culture, the things they talk about, and their ideas are similar. I felt a bit distant to be honest. I think I generally get along better with Europeans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we went outside (we had to wait quite a while even to go out). We met up with our group and attended a not-so-enjoyable panel. After listening for a bit, we went outside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the panels, we went back to the hotel to go to BestBuy. We had arranged it with TÜBİTAK personnel and went and came back within a few hours. Finally got my headphones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/3.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/3_hu12428656057676807317.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/3_hu1378528986506430645.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="An image of half of the area which Student Mixer took place."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then there was the Student Mixer. Party and all. The dinner before that was quite nice. After chatting with my Danish friend for a bit, we returned to the hotel with friends. The &amp;ldquo;you need a teacher to go back to the hotel&amp;rdquo; is no longer relevant. Four of us went to the hotel. On the way back, I met a Turkish researcher interested in my work, who expressed a desire to talk again in the future. Upon arriving at the hotel, I went to the room, reviewed my presentation one last time, and sent a few voice messages to my folks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-6---presentation-day">Day 6 - Presentation Day
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Today is the day. The presentation day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I woke up and took a shower. They said to leave at 7:15, and fortunately, I guessed right and got up at 6:30. We got ready and went downstairs, arriving at the LA Convention Center with a 7-minute delay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After waiting in a long line for a while, we went inside. The first 1.5 hours were for special award judges. There is only one special award suitable for me (besides TÜBİTAK), so I don&amp;rsquo;t expect anyone to come, honestly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 9 judges listed on the paper on my table. You can&amp;rsquo;t be sure if all 9 will come due to no-shows and extras. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what happens. Personally, all I want is for things to go smoothly and well. I can&amp;rsquo;t really think about winning or losing right now. Whatever is meant to be, will be. I&amp;rsquo;ve always said this and always will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As expected, no special awards came in the first 1.5 hours. I have about half an hour until my first judge presentation. Let&amp;rsquo;s see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A leading figure for the new category TECA came. He&amp;rsquo;s a TECA judge but not my judge. We had a nice conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another person with free time came. It went quite well too. I might have not used my best English, but it was still good experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another judge came. He seemed like a good person. He asked a lot of human evaluation questions. I answered all of them, hopefully to his satisfaction. He wanted percentage-wise data a lot. Maybe it would have been better to present something percentage-based instead of confusion matrices, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A judge lady came, an east music singer. It was a nice conversation. I think I presented well. They like the question about whether you want a presentation of different lengths. The previous judge had also mentioned it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just before lunch, a judge came. He exactly looked like a typical American. He came, and before I could even start talking, he started saying random things. He looked at the poster a bit, then talked about his child. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even ask if I should present. Then he started telling stories about his experiences, which had nothing to do with the project. My heart was pounding, trying to find a way to relate it to the project, but I was also afraid of making him dislike me. He&amp;rsquo;s a judge, after all, and pushing him could be disadvantageous for me. Anyway, 15 minutes passed somehow. Right next to me, a different TECA contestant approached me and asked if my experience was terrible too. I said yes, I had never encountered such a judge. Later I learned that he behaved even worse to others, so they complained about him, and he was removed from judging due to the complaints, unable to attend the afternoon sessions. He was a very strange man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For lunch, I had cheese pizza again, quite nice and filling. We sat for a while, and then moved on to the afternoon presentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my first presentation of the afternoon, a very serious judge came. It went well, though. He was into more the technical stuff, asked technical questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then some special award judges came while we were hanging out. They were looking at AI projects, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t present well. Didn&amp;rsquo;t matter much, as they weren&amp;rsquo;t very interested in my work. They gave a couple of gifts and left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The judge I just presented to was really good. I wish I could have presented better. He asked me to explain tokenization in detail. It&amp;rsquo;s tough to explain even if I&amp;rsquo;ve done it hundred times. I think he liked it, though. Hopefully, he&amp;rsquo; did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a 30-minute break now. Three left. After that, another 30-minute break. But then I have two back-to-back judging sessions, without a break. Hopefully, they&amp;rsquo;ll go well too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A strange lady came, just listened with a smile. Said Turkey was nice or something. I&amp;rsquo;m sure she didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to what I was presenting. I wish I had made it shorter so she could leave even earlier. At least she asked a couple of very general questions, like if there was any intellectual property and what could be added in the future and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presented to an LAPD officer. It was weird :).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another judge lady came. I think she liked it. I hope so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I presented to a nice judge. It was going well overall. Then he asked how long I had worked on it. I said a year. He said it was too little. Said to develop it further and left. He asked about limitations too. He was a good guy, but his comment upset me. Oh well. Hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;ll turn out well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now going back to the hotel to rest. Then Universal Studios. I&amp;rsquo;m really tired, but I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll rest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Universal Studios, we hurriedly went up, changed, and came down. Then we got on the bus and started heading to the venue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/4.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/4_hu13761569087810588775.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/4_hu8709467305199966853.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Universal Studios lightened with ISEF logo."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We got off, extremely hungry, and went down to the bottom. First, we went to the Mario Kart thing without knowing it was Mario Kart. When they said food was free, we quickly left and went to the nearest restaurant. Ate chicken and rice at the Jurassic Park-themed place, but both were not my tastes. Had dessert too. Then we went up a bit more, slightly fuller, and walked around. As evening progressed, it got colder, and it got dark. First, we went to a Harry Potter place but didn&amp;rsquo;t go in because we didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it. Then, while randomly walking around, we decided to join the Universal Studios tour. Definitely the best decision we made. They prepared an hour-long program with 3D glasses, huge sets, water sprays, fire, historical events for the universal studios being narrated, comparisons with new ones. It was really, really, really good. Then we walked around a bit more, went to the Hogwarts bathroom, and hopped on the return shuttle. Nice evening. Came back extremely tired but somehow feeling unexpectedly rested. The adrenaline rush might have reversed some things.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-7---public-day--special-awards-ceremony">Day 7 - Public Day &amp;amp; Special Awards Ceremony
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve opened my eyes at 5 in the morning. I wasn’t rested, but I reached for my phone anyway. Checked messages, chatted with a few people. Then I slept for another hour or so and woke up still not feeling rested. Leaving the hotel felt difficult today, to be honest. I was really tired, not just from yesterday, but in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the morning, I had a cookie and went to the venue. First, I joined the TECA crew for breakfast. One of the judges from yesterday gave a presentation. Good man. He works in film production but has a degree in mechanics from Harvard. Quite a career. After that, we played an ice breaker game and took some photos. Then we went back to the venue and started presenting to the arriving visitors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A classical violinist came by. Really solid guy. He asked some sweet questions, both about AI ethics and AI in music in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then a group arrived. I hadn’t dealt with a group like this before. Americans in their 40s, watching in amazement at what the youth are doing. They hung out, chatted a lot. It was great!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lots of people of varying ages stopped by. The guitar attracted quite a bit of attention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My lunch break was pretty odd. My friend from TECA next to me said it was time for lunch. Then a Turkish person who had previously said we should talk later came and invited me for lunch. It turned into a sort of business lunch. He talked about his ideas and his perspective on AI. He suggested a few tokenization approaches regarding to music modeling, which I had already thought about, so I quickly understood and explained.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After lunch, an IFL ’93 graduate who had said he would come by visited our booth. I really liked him. He’s currently a researcher at UCS. He’s been in America for a long time, traveled to different places. He hadn’t planned to stay long when he came for his PhD, but family life changes things, I guess. He enlightened me on a few topics I hadn’t thought about before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After listening to our projects and chatting a bit, I checked WhatsApp and saw that TÜBİTAK personnel said the education attaché from the consulate was coming. I found them and explained the project at the booth. It’s tricky switching between explaining in English and Turkish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then one of the judges from yesterday, the one who presented in the morning, came by with his 4-year-old child. The kid wouldn’t stay still, naturally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that, we said goodbye to our alumnus and returned to the hotel. The public exhibition continued in the afternoon, but I was extremely tired, so I couldn’t say no to the offer to go back. Nice people come, but I really need to rest. My throat and limbs can’t take much more. We’ll be going to a special awards ceremony tonight. I don’t expect to win any special awards. I’d be thrilled if TÜBİTAK gave one, but if not, that’s okay too. There’s an AI special award that I might win, but I doubt it. SOFT has tons of AI projects, so one of them will probably win. We’ll see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just had the special awards ceremony. Turkey had a below-average awards ceremony. We didn’t get the two awards we were expecting, but it’s okay. My friend Leylek and his team got the Qatar award. I didn’t get the TÜBİTAK special award, but that’s fine; it went to our friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the awards ceremony, I went to the room, packed up, and went straight to bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-8---grand-awards-ceremony">Day 8 - Grand Awards Ceremony
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I woke up around 5:00 AM for some reason. Sent a few messages, tried to sleep again around 5:30 for another hour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then went downstairs, checked out, and put our luggage in the luggage room. God, I hope nothing happens to the guitar. I brought it all this way without problems, and I definitely don’t want any damage now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It took forever to leave the hotel, of course. We headed to the main awards ceremony hall again. From now on, fingers crossed.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Just like in the Ankara Finals, my corner is great. But np, it is the moment which the biggest dice are rolling. Best of luck. &lt;em>-Leylek Corner&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exciting award ceremony. The order was 4-3-2-category change-then 1st places at the last. Each category, we wondered if we had a project in it. Great moments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, my schoolers got 2nd place, then I did. And that wrapped up the award ceremony. Not a great result for Turkey. Including the special awards from yesterday, we got 6 awards in total.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It felt weird. I feel weird. Like at the finals, I fell into a void again. I didn’t know how to feel. Especially after our alumnus’s talk yesterday. It made me feel a bit insignificant. Even though I had thought about it before, whether I’d win or not, having my plans and dreams suddenly become real was overwhelming. I don’t like award ceremonies, whether I’m receiving an award or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now it’s time to head back. We’ll be on the road for hours, maybe even a day. Traveling is long, boring, and especially tiring. Let’s see.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. &lt;em>-Leylek&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/5.webp"
width="1600"
height="1200"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/5_hu17746215990673686807.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/isef_travel/5_hu1478994205543471129.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Me, just after winning the 2nd place."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="final-words-and-evaluation-of-the-event">Final Words and Evaluation of the Event
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Thoughts on the event in general:&lt;/strong> It’s a good event, definitely not bad. Huge event. Organization-wise, really solid; everyone does their job well. But the first days are quite boring. A lot of uninteresting symposiums. I could say it’s just me or us, but no, it’s like that for everyone you can see it by looking at the number of attendees. Other than that, they stick to the schedule, they’re helpful, they notify everything via email and phone app, etc. The judges were sweet and fun to talk to. The best and most enjoyable day went well, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On what this event brought me:&lt;/strong> I’m glad I came, whether I won an award or not (I’m writing this the day before the award ceremony because I might not bother with evaluations once I’m home.) I’m glad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing America early was nice, at least CA/LA. I got a bit of understanding of the structure. I saw its people. Throughout the event, I chatted with lots of people, both locals and foreigners, both from afar and up close. On the public day, if I hadn’t been so tired in the afternoon and stayed at the booth, I might have met even more people, but that’s okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My presentation skills and language proficiency improved quite a bit. I saw more clearly where I got stuck and what I did well. I realized I’m not that bad at design and poster preparation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As I wrote in the ISTF24 report:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am eternally grateful to TÜBİTAK for giving me the opportunity to represent my country.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>ISTF Event</title><link>https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note (EN):&lt;/strong> If you know Turkish, I highly recommend you to read this article in Turkish. Beacuse it is the original version.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Not (TR):&lt;/strong> Yazının orijinal versiyonu Türkçe olduğundan dolayı eğer biliyorsanız bu yazıyı Türkçe okumanızı tavsiye ederim.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="day-1">Day 1
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Not day 0 because there are half-day activities upon arrival.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We woke up at 3 AM and arrived in Izmir. I took the Izmir-SAW flight without any issues with baggage or transitions. I&amp;rsquo;m getting used to this!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I reached SAW, wandered a bit, found the international departures, and my gate was right there in line. I waited for a while, wrote some things on my phone, and listened to music. I boarded the plane and took my seat, 40E, the last row middle seat—the worst technically. But the back was pretty empty, so I moved to a three-seater alone. Nice, I was a bit sleepy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, we landed in Zurich without any problems. I slept for about an hour and wrote a bit. They only allowed exit from the front door, and I was at the very back. Sad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had an adrenaline-filled 15 minutes. Passport control and baggage claim were smooth. I followed the signs to the train, which was easy. Their train ticket system is very clean. I saw the SBB mobile app for the train location. I bought the first train to Notwill with few transfers. It was leaving in 5 minutes, and I had no idea where it was. I randomly took an escalator down, asked an elderly couple about the train. The man checked on the app, said I had to go to the center first, then Luzern, then Notwill in 20 minutes. We talked again while getting off the train, he showed me the wagons and took a photo of the SBB screen. I realized I could access saved routes offline. It was epic. Now I&amp;rsquo;m a bit relaxed, hope I won&amp;rsquo;t have issues with other trains. I&amp;rsquo;m going to the last stop for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Met the happiest ticket inspector ever. Scans tickets on the phone, punches holes in physical tickets, and writes stuff. So strange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two more trains to Notwill. Nice journeys. Walked a bit to the hotel, checked in, and met my roommate who arrived yesterday with his father. We got our name tags and goodies together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At 3 PM, we had a meeting with Julian Cancino, the ISTF organization leader. He introduced the team and explained the process. Our schedule is well planned out in the booklets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we did an icebreaker where we changed partners every two minutes. Chatted with different people, including someone from my team who came through EUCYS!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, we met with our full team. Played four games: drew each other&amp;rsquo;s faces without looking at the paper and introduced ourselves, built a bridge with a single sheet of paper and tape in random teams without talking, had a talking competition in two teams with more paper and tape, and did a post-it activity about main contributions, what we want from others, and our weaknesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We went to dinner together, although I ended up sitting alone for a bit. Then some friends from team 5B joined. We chatted a lot, I spoke some German, one was Swiss, the other Swedish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I excused myself and returned to the room, talked to my folks. Managed to set up the internet eventually, thank goodness. Slept around 9:30 PM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-2">Day 2
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Woke up at 7:10 AM (snoozed 7 alarms) and went to breakfast around 7:30 AM with Swiss bodybuilders and web app developers. Not bad guys. Then, I worked on the report for half an hour. Later, some bigwigs were going to give an opening speech.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The head, around 70 years old, spoke without notes. Learned the clarinet at 70, amazing man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then Karen talked for an hour about intelligence and learning. Interesting topics but boring delivery. She said non-smart people shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go to uni as they struggle at ETH. Tough stance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a coffee break, we met with teams and our Challenger. Nice woman from England, married to a Dane. She verbally went over the presentation she sent earlier. We introduced ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lunch was good, chatted with the bodybuilders about the education system and elections. Chill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We went to team rooms and brainstormed. I don&amp;rsquo;t I had done brainstorming before after seeing this. My team had different perspectives, which was really great. Coming from various backgrounds led us to create various ideas too. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t define AI well, but I explained and they researched a bit. Must-reads helped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Took a walk, then spent 3-4 hours in the team room. Found good ideas but struggled to combine them. Ended with a simple problem statement and a decent solution. We&amp;rsquo;ll refine it tomorrow, maybe design a UI idk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, other groups presented their problem statements with Challengers. Then dinner. I might work on the report tonight. Tomorrow, we&amp;rsquo;ll brainstorm a different problem statement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/1.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/1_hu3510391214733028393.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/1_hu2666380075670473441.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="An image from Aula the conference hall."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen led Challenger presentations, asked odd questions. All five Challengers were good, but ours seemed the best. Very energetic and passionate about AI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dinner was nice and filling. Sat with the wrong group though, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t like their style of talking. I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed a few things regarding to the event with my teammates, then excused myself to work on the report. Aiming to finish it this week.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-3">Day 3
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Worked late into the night, got a lot done. Woke up a few times to check the time. Got up at 7:15 AM, ate some pastries. Woke my roommate, not sure if he&amp;rsquo;ll make it to breakfast. I&amp;rsquo;m full but I don’t want him to skip.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At breakfast, had juice and chatted with the Guacamole friend. Roommate joined last minute. Then we went to the Aula, learned the day&amp;rsquo;s schedule. Did storyboarding on other groups&amp;rsquo; problem statements. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s suitable for every topic. Drawing with those pens was not the greatest experience imho.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We shared our drawings, talked about copyright issues which was the Challenge 4. I don&amp;rsquo;t like these issues tbh. Everyone agreed with me and they wanted to move onto our own problem statement too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Returned to the Aula for a decision-making conference. Enjoyed it but for some reason I struggled to stay awake. Now-How-Wow framework was interesting, need the slides from MS Teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a dull coffee break, we reviewed each other’s storyboards. One was similar to our AI classmate idea. I skimmed it and wrote notes. We had a clear idea, unsure how we’ll spend the day. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to do in Luzerne trip, eat something or just walk around Luzern? Because there is no dinner today but a Luzerne trip with 30 CHF for food. Not sure what I&amp;rsquo;ll do or who I&amp;rsquo;ll hang out with. We’ll see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ended the day with a brief chat with Chantalle (our Challenger). She’s sweet but her AI knowledge is unclear. Quite optimistic. Today was a bit pointless, especially the first 3 hours. We had a good idea already, just needed to finalize it. But eventually we started asking each other questions to clarify some concepts then figured out the whole thing. Not entirely happy with the day, but the evening was great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Went to Luzerne with the team captain (nicknamed dictator). Nice person, loves pushing herself. Hung out with the Swiss-Danish-Swedish friends. Played cards, discussed politics, ate pizza. Wandered around in the rain, took photos. Sat with the Danish teammate on the way back.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-4">Day 4
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Showered in the morning. Breakfast with the bodybuilders, no one else was free. Ate quickly, then headed to the Aula.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introductions, then masterclasses. Made a mistake, should have taken story building instead of presentation creation. Didn&amp;rsquo;t learn much but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad. I think we needed more real examples. He asked us for feedbacks and this was everyones agreed opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then came work hours. We needed to present our core message to the story builder people. Not sure why. We&amp;rsquo;re crafting a good sentence. I’m preparing the presentation, but two others will present. Thank goodness I won&amp;rsquo;t be presenting. We’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/2.webp"
width="4224"
height="3136"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/2_hu2120712119560969960.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/2_hu12919887141104045582.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Teammates!"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="134"
data-flex-basis="323px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spent the whole day on the presentation. The dictator didn&amp;rsquo;t like my style but at least I found a color palette. Didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like eating dinner. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t do everything I wanted. Different thinking styles we have with the team captain. But eventually I followed their ideas, it’s their presentation. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve done the correct decision by doing so. A tiring day, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had worse xd.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we’re going to the lake. Feels like a big mistake, but let&amp;rsquo;s see. Hope we don’t return too late.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lake was beautiful, definitely a good experience. Initially reluctant but ended up enjoying it. On the way back, talked with friends about languages. Interesting people worldwide!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-5">Day 5
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Woke up, no sign of my roommate. He arrived just as I was leaving. Told me to go ahead and I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had breakfast with the team, then went to the team rooms. We had a document to fill out AI prompts and some info. We didn&amp;rsquo;t rush before, good call as they gave us time to complete it. Then we drew a &lt;em>graph of our week&lt;/em> and shared our biggest takeaway. Now doing the green room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Walked around the hotel for the green room. The cold was refreshing. Looking forward to the presentations. We’re last, but I want to photograph projects and people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the green room, we went to the hall. We’re the last on the schedule. Until then, it’s listening to others. Then our friends will present, we’ll take the stage, answer a few questions, and done. I&amp;rsquo;m not nervous for myself but for the presenters. Hope it goes well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amazing presentations, especially one girl who blew us away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the coffee break, chatted with Ozgurkaraca and Leylek from the folks. Chill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our turn came, and the presentation went well. People liked it, ended nicely with a height-equality analogy. We took the stage, no nerves in a group. Chantelle gave feedback, always cheerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Topic leader challenged our project’s core idea. Danish teammate countered, got applause. Intense moments! We were second last. Afterwards, Chantelle disagreed with the topic leader too. Huge applause for her too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julian wrapped up, told us to chill and eat. Dinner was a stand-up meal in the Foyer, only 30 guests. We thanked Chantelle as a team for her support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Afterwards, went to the lake with departing friends&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A peaceful end, chatted till late, shared photos. Overall, a fulfilling week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/3.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/3_hu10873130571905122317.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/istf_travel/3_hu16543811111468488694.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="An image of a beautiful morning we woke up to."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="final-words">Final Words
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This is how you run an event, my friend. Everything happened with a max-min delay of 3 minutes. Beyond the timing aspect, the event was packed with a variety of activities, managed 80 participants smoothly, and included many small details that seemed insignificant to us but were very well organized (for example, the visualization activity: each team explained the core idea of their problem and solution to an artist, who then drew it, and we used that in our presentation).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had tiring times, and there were also quite boring moments for the team. Sometimes our mood dropped due to fatigue and/or boredom. Other times, we laughed until we were exhausted. Especially on the fourth day, Friday, amidst all the work, we had quite a bit of fun imitating British accents. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the start of the event, I mentioned to people that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much experience working seriously with others. (We did GYEC twice, but it was all day and with people I already knew, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly like this.) I feel like I really gained good experience in this regard. Spending three to four days brainstorming with people you don&amp;rsquo;t know at all, listening to them, understanding them, and explaining your points. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work. But it was really enjoyable. From building a bridge to drawing a graph of how the week went, I enjoyed every group activity. We caught a good synergy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Language. We had a Portuguese friend in the team who had a slight problem with English. We understood him, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t use crazy words, and his accent was plain. He lacked confidence at first, but he opened up quite a bit later. Good friend. To be honest, I had some difficulties with the language in some places. No problem with basic things, but whenever we delved into a specific area, if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t my field, I got stuck. I really need to work on my vocabulary. I learned new words here, but there are still critical words I don&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll sit down and seriously study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Europe is strange. We talked about many different topics with friends from various nationalities. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember everything, nor did I feel the need to write it all down. But I can say that their systems are very different from ours. For example, in their education systems, they really focus on the individual, considering their differences. I heard amazing things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve finished my general thoughts, I&amp;rsquo;m writing my last sentences in the hotel room, while my roommate (and his father) are hanging out to my left. I had a really great week; the places I saw, the people I met, all the activities I did, the many presentations I listened to&amp;hellip; As I wrote in the report for TÜBİTAK,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I would like to express my endless gratitude to TÜBİTAK for giving me the opportunity to represent my country.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>EUCYS Competition</title><link>https://fansesi.github.io/p/eucys_travel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fansesi.github.io/p/eucys_travel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note (EN):&lt;/strong> If you know Turkish, I highly recommend you to read this article in Turkish. Beacuse it is the original version.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Not (TR):&lt;/strong> Yazının orijinal versiyonu Türkçe olduğundan dolayı eğer biliyorsanız bu yazıyı Türkçe okumanızı tavsiye ederim.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="day-0---travel">Day 0 - Travel
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>First. Time. Just myself. Plane. Crazy stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s 2:40 AM. Left my friends about an hour ago. I&amp;rsquo;ve headed to the airport. Passed through the first entrance gate. Then checked in my luggage. They took my poster too. Hopefully, nothing happens to it. Then passed through the check-in code scanning area. Overall, it was easy. I&amp;rsquo;m hungry and thirsty. Don&amp;rsquo;t know why. I have a headache. Am I stressed? Not sure. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just sleep-deprived. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait for an hour at the gate. Continuing listening to Hiromi-sama.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arrived in Istanbul. Collected the bags, and then it was time for the Ankara team to arrive. Waited and waited, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t show up. Turns out they went to the international terminal and checked in their bags. Anyway, I checked in mine too. Then we sat and waited for our flight. Time passed somehow. We boarded the plane and landed in Brussels. There was a very long passport line. Then the bags came. Boring stuff. After the airport, we took a bus to the hotel. It took a quite a long time for some reason. Everyone except us was happy. For them, this contest is just a fun event, but for us, it could change our fate. Very frustrating. We passed by the Atomium. Memories&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arrived at the hotel. The rooms are quite small. Hopefully, we won&amp;rsquo;t be spending much time in the hotel, just for sleeping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dinner was at a different restaurant. We walked 15 minutes to get there. They first served pork, which we found out later. Then came some chicken. Unfortunately, the food wasn&amp;rsquo;t to our taste. Then we went to Carrefour and got some water. At least we have water now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll do one more run-through of my presentation before sleeping. I need to think about how to present it to the visitors. But I&amp;rsquo;m very tired. My roommate is a nice fellow, but he has work to do too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-1---start-of-the-exhibition-and-jury-sessions">Day 1 - Start of The Exhibition and Jury Sessions
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A nice breakfast in the morning. Then headed to the venue. Collected our belongings from the desk. Ömer Faruk Ursavaş helped me with my poster. Quite an honor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Waved the flag at the opening ceremony. Chatted a lot with people from different countries. Fun times. Now I&amp;rsquo;m hanging out at the stand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had a few visitors. I don&amp;rsquo;t stumble much while talking. The poster behind me really supports me. I&amp;rsquo;m quite proud of it because it seems to be the best-looking one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lunch was a small piece of bread with cheese. The cheese tasted good, can&amp;rsquo;t lie. No idea if I ate anything or if I&amp;rsquo;m full tho. My stomach isn&amp;rsquo;t great, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really understand if I ate, if I&amp;rsquo;m hungry, or if I&amp;rsquo;m full.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just spoke with an old jury member. He&amp;rsquo;s been a guitarist for 58 years. 58 years! Said he would come to listen later or send someone. Nice that he&amp;rsquo;s interested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the exhibition, there was a talk by EIROForum, an EU fusion research institute. Not exactly my field, but it was still nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After packing up at the exhibit and having dinner, we returned to the hotel. Called friends and family in Türkiye and went to bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-2---jury-sessions-cont">Day 2 - Jury Sessions Cont.
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Woke up in the morning, or rather, kept delaying getting up until it was 8:00 AM. Got dressed and went down for breakfast. The hotel&amp;rsquo;s breakfast is quite nice, I like it. Had a bite to eat and walked up a few steep slopes to get to the venue. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how today goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll wander around a bit before the exhibit starts. Not to check out the competition, but to see what projects are there. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to evaluate every project while everyone is at the competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, this jury presentation didn&amp;rsquo;t go very well. I forgot the beginning part of my presentation. One jury member came who didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to know much technical stuff. When interrupted, I forgot what I was going to say. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad, but worse than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just talked to an Ableton user. It was enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One more jury, making it three. This one was a chemist. I quickly went through the technical parts. He seriously asked why personalization is important, and I said, &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a paper.&amp;rdquo; Overall, it was probably good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Participants across from me liked the poster and even took a photo. Romanians are nice people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another jury, making it four. This one was really an engineer, even had a music-based startup two years ago. The presentation went well, and he asked good questions, both technical and conversational. Said he would inform a few friends who might get in touch with me. Quite a nice chat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Told my Romanian friends about my real roommate Aliberk. They have similar interests!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, a Lithuanian competitor came by. Recently graduated too. We talked a lot. Reminded me of a friend with her demeanor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I was packing up to leave, a jury member suddenly appeared behind me. The exhibit time was over. We talked briefly about the project; I landed a hook on him, and he said he would come back tomorrow. Hopefully, that will go well, and I won&amp;rsquo;t have major issues with the jury presentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After leaving the exhibit, we went for a walk around the area. Palaces and stuff. Then went for a hamburger. Hate to say it, but it was the best meal we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the last few days. Then returned to the hotel, dropped our stuff, and went out again. Bought chocolates and souvenirs. Hung out mostly with my roommate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back at the hotel, took a shower and went to bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-3---jury-sessions-cont">Day 3 - Jury Sessions Cont.
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Woke up, got ready. After breakfast, went to the venue. Nothing unusual. The juries are making their final decisions, making their rounds. Most of us have had four jury visits; we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for our last ones. I expected mine to come early, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet (it&amp;rsquo;s only been 30 minutes, though). Listened to Tank from Seatbelts to wake myself up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The jury came in the morning. Didn&amp;rsquo;t even do the full presentation; he wanted to listen, we chatted a bit, and then he left. It was quite pleasant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had quite a few visitors afterward. My throat started to hurt :). At one point, someone from Huawei came. Left a business card for an internship, gave a small plush bear, and left. There was a guy and a lady; while I was explaining to the guy, the lady took photos, etc. I had started a technical presentation since I first asked the guy about his field but didn&amp;rsquo;t know they were from Huawei. Found out at the end of the conversation. Quite impressive. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll apply for their internship programs when I get to university.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had lunch just now. They added cake (which I don&amp;rsquo;t think was there before). It tasted good, but not really my thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The afternoon is chill. Maybe the jury will come one last time, but I doubt it. I think we can say we&amp;rsquo;ve closed the exhibit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As expected, no other jury came, and I closed the exhibit. Walked around a bit, hung out with the Lithuanian. Then we took down the posters. Unfortunately, had to throw them away because it would be too hard to carry them. Won&amp;rsquo;t use them again anyway. They were torn too. Still, I can&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to throw them away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we went back to the hotel. After resting, we went to the Belgian Diner. Don&amp;rsquo;t want to offend anyone, but just fries? Really?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Talked to a lot of people on voice/video calls in the room. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to finish writing and go to bed because I&amp;rsquo;m tired, hungry, thirsty, and sleep is the cure for all these (sort of).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-4---award-ceremony-and-poster-take-off">Day 4 - Award Ceremony and Poster Take Off
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The day of the award ceremony. The most important event of the day. Imagine, my life might completely change in 5-6 hours. Crazy situation I&amp;rsquo;m in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woke up and had breakfast. Going to Media Markt. The guys want to look for headphones because they&amp;rsquo;re cheaper here. If I find a nice one, I might buy it too, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be more selective than them. Need to compare prices with Türkiye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After some research, I found a good pair of headphones online. But unfortunately, the Media Markt we went to had only one in stock, so they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t sell it. Thought about going for something much more expensive, but I&amp;rsquo;m not prepared for that. If I&amp;rsquo;m spending that much, I need to find the best one for me. So I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy anything. My current plan is to buy a classic JBL and get the headphones from the US. Or maybe from Türkiye, not sure. But not from here, no.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At Media Markt, there were also Switch, PS5, Xbox, etc. Maybe later, not now. They also had Blu-rays and boxed games. Those were very nice. Albums too. Would have bought Nostradamus if I found it, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded the 10-15 euros, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Waited for the bus for over 15 minutes to get to the award ceremony. When we got there, we just wasted time waiting for it to start. After gathering in the hall for the ceremony, it was the participants&amp;rsquo; turn to waste time. Then the awards were announced. A ton of special awards. Good, nice. Didn&amp;rsquo;t expect or want any of them. When it came to the core prizes, things got more exciting. 7-8 of the core prize winners got special awards too, which both frustrated and saddened us. We didn&amp;rsquo;t stay for the party. Our mood was down a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now resting. Tomorrow will be all about traveling. Not planning to write anything for tomorrow. Unless something extraordinary happens, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write about the hours we spend waiting at the airport.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-5---departure">Day 5 - Departure
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Couldn&amp;rsquo;t wake up to the 3:30 AM alarm. Ended up getting ready at 4:00 AM when the TÜBİTAK officer called for the 4:15 ride. Not great, forgot my charger there. Nothing to be done. Then waited half an hour for the car. Not a great organization, unfortunately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The airport and the plane were generally uneventful. Routine procedures, nothing interesting. In the end, we didn&amp;rsquo;t come back from EUCYS with what we expected. Their culture seems a bit strange to me. I miss Türkiye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This contest changed my view of the EU. Very different lives people are living. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to study in the EU now. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel like dealing with applications either. Maybe my thoughts will change when I get home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really want to go home, get back to normal, have proper meals, drink water, and speak Turkish freely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2204A 2023 Türkiye Finals</title><link>https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note (EN):&lt;/strong> If you know Turkish, I highly recommend you to read this article in Turkish. Beacuse it is the original version.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Not (TR):&lt;/strong> Yazının orijinal versiyonu Türkçe olduğundan dolayı eğer biliyorsanız bu yazıyı Türkçe okumanızı tavsiye ederim.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="day-0---saturday-night">Day 0 - Saturday Night
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Bus ride. It had been a long time since I last took a bus. But sitting in a single seat is comfortable, more spacious than I expected. I put my guitar next to Hakan Hoca. It seems safe there. Things are good. I might fall asleep soon, or maybe listen to the Skyrim album like I did on the way to Paris? Tough decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finished the Skyrim album. Then I thought of listening to Hiromi, but it was too much jazz for the night.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-1---sunday">Day 1 - Sunday
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>There was no breakfast at the hotel, so we went out for breakfast. We had pizza with Leylek. It was quite good. Afterward, we walked around a lot. There were big markets. It was fascinating to see how the concept of street markets had completely disappeared in big cities, with vendors inside those huge markets throwing vegetables and fruits into bags. Interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I’m back and resting. After lying down for a bit, I’ll probably review the presentation again. Then dinner. We’ll likely review it one last time after dinner and try to sleep early.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up sleeping until dinner. It was refreshing. The dinner was good, though I got scolded for taking too little food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After dinner, I worked on the presentation, went through it three times, and played a lot of guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-2---monday---start-of-the-exhibition">Day 2 - Monday - Start of the Exhibition
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/1.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/1_hu5076695400600233585.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/1_hu6481157098991251629.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image of my poster and my beloved guitar in the corner!"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rushed breakfast in the morning. Now we’re on the bus. This part could have been planned a bit better, but no big deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the morning, I met a nice guy sitting next to me, an electric guitarist. Good conversations we had. Despite being my competitor, I didn’t sense any ego just like other people have. Seems like a good guy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of my competitors came over and asked silly questions. They seemed either condescending or scared, not sure. I might confront them later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guy we met at IYTE last year when doing physics is here again. Name is Eren. Nice, friendly guy. We hung out with him and his friend, both pianists. We talked about music theory, etc. Enjoyed it!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was also a guy who claimed to be a bass guitarist. The first thing he asked was if I paid attention to root positions. He mentioned his interest in theory. Also, while I was playing Asturias for someone, a middle school girl came up and said, &amp;ldquo;Isn’t this Isaac Albeniz’s Asturias?&amp;rdquo; Cool stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For dinner, while looking for a spot with Leylek, we saw Eren’s table was empty. We decided to join them. Another guy was sitting with Eren.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the evening, I spent quite a bit of time with Leylek. I listened to their presentations, and they listened to mine. We brainstormed what could be improved. It was helpful, I think. I shortened a few points. I’ll continue tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-3---tuesday---presentation-day">Day 3 - Tuesday - Presentation Day
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/2.webp"
width="1600"
height="720"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/2_hu2165158168237958918.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/2_hu3863220056838726045.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The exhibition from upstairs."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="222"
data-flex-basis="533px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I couldn’t sleep well anyway. I kept debating whether to get up or not. I had time, but I didn’t feel like getting up. Eventually, I managed to go down for breakfast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had a nice breakfast. Tried the chocolate with hazelnut pieces my brother suggested from the market. It was quite good. We ate a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We wore the red shirts they gave us yesterday for breakfast. I liked them a lot; I’ll probably wear them again later. There’s also a coat, but it doesn’t seem very useful. We’ll see where to use it later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A guy from Adana BILSEM came, talking about using LSTM in the music industry. The LSTM didn’t perform well. They didn’t make it to the finals. It’s unfortunate for them. But it breaks my assumption that there are no synthetic data generators in 2204A. There are, but they perform poorly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was announced yesterday that there would be jury presentations. We thought they’d be more likely the next day. It wasn’t, so we did our presentations today. At least I and my roommate did; Leylek will present tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the morning, we went to the stand and saw men in suits with briefcases walking around. They were the jury. The art teacher from my region is also here as a jury member. I recognized him while walking around in the morning. When he came to the stand, I realized it was him. There was another guy with him, very cold; he didn’t show much interest while I was explaining and didn’t ask questions during the presentation. It raises some suspicion because it could go either way. I don’t think I made any big mistakes in the presentation. I answered the questions well. They didn’t ask the challenging ones I expected. The questions were easier, and I answered them. Anyway, we’ll learn the result on Friday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Afterward, I reviewed high school math projects. Honestly, almost all of them are garbage. I couldn’t listen to the matrix project from the TAKEV crew; the girl is so chill that her stand is empty all day. Besides that, there’s nothing noteworthy. Middle school math projects were much more enjoyable to listen to. High school projects are really boring in that regard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also randomly listened to one sociology, one education, and one literature project. After one, I don’t think I can listen to another one. These fields are generally not for me. I listened to one chemistry project from the 9th graders. It wasn’t that bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly, I toured a middle school project with the TAKEV crew. We checked out one bio, one chemistry, and one physics project. Two out of three people at the bio stand were girls with excellent diction. Impressive. It was enjoyable to listen to; I wish I could have asked better questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, that’s how it went. The rest of the exhibition is quite calm now. I’ve seen most of it, and I’ll try to make a few more friends. I’ll try to befriend the guys next to us. I already have, but I want to get closer. The guys there seem decent. There are a few more guys from software design, but I’m not trying to befriend them for some reason. I don’t know why. We’ll see tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a bit, I’ll head to the mezzanine to hang out with Leylek. I’ll hang out there for a while, then come back to sleep. That’s the plan!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P.S.: I studied math olympiad at Leylek’s place in the evening, then went to bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-4---wednesday---public-day">Day 4 - Wednesday - Public Day
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/3.webp"
width="4000"
height="2248"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/3_hu13842501914014817705.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/3_hu9192672818249060237.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The Amazing Leylek!"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="427px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m quite late in writing today’s events, but I don’t want to leave it for the next day because it would overlap with that day, and I might get lazy. So I’m planning to write and then sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I caused a bit of a mess at breakfast. Trying a bit of everything was a bit heavy, honestly. Especially pure tahini, I discovered, is tough to eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After breakfast, we went to the exhibition as usual. The roads are the same, the first moves are generally the same. My goal today was to visit the last few exhibits and connect more with the new people I met. I think I did that. I spent quite a bit of time at the stand in the morning. I had a lot of visitors, especially compared to my previous project. I saw many different people throughout the exhibition. It was quite satisfying. At some point, I started giving almost perfect presentations. Every sentence and word seemed to be the best choice. Telling the same thing a zillion times really improves you. Now I understand why teachers are so knowledgeable about the subjects they teach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the morning, the press shot about a 1-minute video of us. More precisely, a guy with a camera and a “PRESS” badge written with a CD marker on his card was trying to record everyone’s exhibition presentations, and eventually, he came to us. I worked on it a bit, presented it, and moved on. It was clean, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After many visitors, the lunch break came quickly. After a nice meal, we hung out with Leylek for a bit. Then I noticed someone from the TAKEV crew, and we toured a few more projects together. After a few projects, we returned to our stand and talked about calc stuff. The guy had been working on calc for a long time and learned new things, which he shared. It was enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, while hanging out with them, a few visitors came by. I explained to them as well. But one of the visitors was one of the two guys who went to ISEF last year. Their field is probably software design too. They had come on the first day of the exhibition, but this time they came with notes. Apparently, they were measuring if we were good enough for ISEF. They asked silly questions to others as I&amp;rsquo;ve heard but couldn’t ask me much because either I explained well, or they didn’t understand properly. Not sure. We’ll see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the afternoon, Hasan Mandal and Ursavaş came. Ursavaş held a 2-3 hour conference with the teachers. Then Hasan Mandal spent about an hour with us. He talked about the things TÜBİTAK does. Then there was a silly Q&amp;amp;A. Middle schoolers, what can you say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We got back to the hotel a bit late due to the conference. After dinner, we spent hours deciding what to do and finally decided to go for a walk. We walked a few laps, bought some stuff from the market, and then came back to the hotel and played a storytelling game while munching on the snacks we bought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow is the tour. Let’s see how it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P.S.: I met an IFL 2002 graduate today, but forgot to mention. I’m curious if I’ll see an IFL student when I grow up and attend high school.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-5---thursday---ankara-tour">Day 5 - Thursday - Ankara Tour
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Every morning, our wake-up time shifts by about half an hour. This morning, we woke up a bit late. We were actually planning to wake up even later, but since my roommate had to get up earlier, I woke up early too. I think the air conditioner got to us a bit; we woke up with sore throats. It&amp;rsquo;s still not quite well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I keep eating these breakfast buffets, I really feel like I&amp;rsquo;m going to gain weight. We actually have the option to eat healthier because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fruits and vegetables, but you just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it. So honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this adventure ending so I can get back to my proper dorm routine. It&amp;rsquo;s nice and all, but only to a certain extent. You need to create a routine here, but there&amp;rsquo;s no need since we&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving soon anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After breakfast, we jumped on the bus and went to the National Library. It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice place. A huge building. There were quite a few people inside. They even have free food and drink services. And, of course, lots of books. If I end up studying in Ankara, I&amp;rsquo;d like it to be a place I visit often.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, we went to the Museum of Anatolian Civilizations. It&amp;rsquo;s a place with artifacts from different civilizations that lived in Anatolia. That place was also very impressive. There were truly captivating figures. In the future, if we print 3D figures themed around bronze, stone, and ceramics, I took lots of photos for reference. I even made one of them my profile picture, a half-faced guy. This place was really great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were supposed to return from the trip at 17:30, but we got back around 15:40. We went shopping with the teachers for some snacks for the evening&amp;rsquo;s movie night. I&amp;rsquo;m even downloading the movie right now. Resting a bit too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the evening, we had a movie night. Only one teacher stayed to watch with us. Everyone else left. It seemed like everyone wanted to watch a movie. Especially &lt;em>Leylek&lt;/em>, who is next to me right now, never wanted to watch it. Afterwards, we chatted with the TAKEV group for about 2 hours. Cool conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-6---friday---award-ceremony">Day 6 - Friday - Award Ceremony
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We woke up in the morning. We didn&amp;rsquo;t really sleep, but I&amp;rsquo;m not tired. Probably because I slept in the afternoon yesterday. We actually left the room late, but the only problem was having to carry the suitcase up eight flights of stairs because we couldn&amp;rsquo;t use the elevator. We checked out of the hotel and had breakfast. I had even less appetite compared to other days, but I still ate something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we&amp;rsquo;re back at the venue. We&amp;rsquo;re waiting around to give our presentation to the suit-wearing officials if they come. Waiting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rest is what I wrote on the bus, trying to relieve the fatigue of the week a bit. The 2204A Final is over; let me explain how it ended.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we were waiting for the officials, we were tearing down the poster. Just then, a guy from ISEF, one of the people who asked me questions, came by. This time he asked for my phone number. He said I was likely to win a prize. Tbh, when he said that, I already understood that I would get first place. But still, you have that &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; question in your mind, so while waiting in that crowded hall, with software design being announced last, your heart still beats very strongly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The officials only came for the award ceremony. We gathered in the crowded hall, and after the VTR and protocol speeches, they started with the awards. Since the Minister of Industry had other engagements, the first prizes were given first. When they announced &amp;ldquo;Izmir&amp;rdquo; during the software design category, my friends were already sending me off to the stage with punches. It was joyful. I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely happy to have a photo with Hasan Mandal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/4.webp"
width="1600"
height="778"
srcset="https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/4_hu12711150440193410765.webp 480w, https://fansesi.github.io/p/2204a_2023_travel/4_hu13183927390927098191.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The photo of me after I got the first prize."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="205"
data-flex-basis="493px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that, Leylek&amp;rsquo;s team got second place, and our my roomamate got first place too. We took photos with the TAKEV group and amongst ourselves. During this time, Ismail Abi came outside. I met the Karaman Provincial Director of National Education, which was quite crazy. Then we went to AŞTİ for food. After that, we got back on the bus. Now, we&amp;rsquo;re moving on the bus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tiring six days, a pleasant six days. But really, the end of the day was incredible. I think I&amp;rsquo;m happy. But I&amp;rsquo;m also confused. University selection, ISEF&amp;hellip; I need to do a lot of research. I&amp;rsquo;ve given myself a lot of work to do, lol.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I cannot thank enough to my brother, mom and dad for their endless support. I&amp;rsquo;d also want to thank my friends and school for their trust in me.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>